{
    "id": "c53e4e01a18d4312b8c5425555a22fef",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We often ……………………… to the cinema on Sundays.",
            "description": "The simple present tense is used to talk about things that happen regularly.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "are going",
                "goes"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………. a lot of TV.",
            "description": "The simple present tense is used to talk about things that happen regularly.",
            "answers": [
                "is watching",
                "watches",
                "will watch"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I can’t come out – I …………………………. my homework.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about things that are happening now.",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "am doing",
                "have been doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………….. with her parents now.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about things that are happening now.",
            "answers": [
                "stays",
                "is staying",
                "has been staying"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………………. in Mumbai for six months.",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous tense is used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "is working",
                "works",
                "has been working"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. to New York next week.",
            "description": "The present continuous is also used to talk about arrangements for future events.",
            "answers": [
                "fly",
                "am flying",
                "will fly"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. Alice in the cafe.",
            "description": "The simple past is used for single actions in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "met",
                "have met",
                "had met"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was in Singapore, I often ………………………. lunch with her.",
            "description": "The simple past is also used for repeated actions in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "would have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The family ………………………….. an outing at the beach last weekend.",
            "description": "The simple past is used for single actions in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "enjoys",
                "has enjoyed",
                "enjoyed"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………………. in the kitchen when Dad came in.",
            "description": "The past continuous is used to talk about actions or situations that were going on at a particular point of time in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "sat",
                "are sitting",
                "were sitting"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………………. you later.",
            "description": "The simple future is used to talk about things in the future.",
            "answers": [
                "phone",
                "will phone",
                "would phone"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………….. her plants as she does her children.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "mothered",
                "mothers",
                "is mothering"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}